MELISSA SCHNEIDER

UI DESIGNER & FRONTEND DEVELOPER



melissajschneider



behance.net/melissaschneid6

https://melschne1975.github.io/website-portfolio-final1/

PROFILE

Passionate UI designer with over 10 years of experience in education. Skilled in problem-solving, leadership, and creativity as evidenced by becoming a supervisor for my last 2 organizations and solving solutions for over 1000 clients. Seeking an organization that values creativity and also promotes growth and success.

812-230-6645

melissaschneider011475@gmail.com

Terre Haute, IN 47802

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE USER INTERFACE DESIGN

- 2023 - 2024 CareerFoundry

CERTIFICATE FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

2023 - 2024 CareerFoundry

BS DEGREE ELEMENTARY EDUCATION

Eastern Illinois University

HARD SKILLS

- USER EXPERIENCE
- UI DESIGN
- PROTOTYPE DESIGN
- · COLLABORATION
- · USABILITY DESIGN
- UX RESEARCH · GRAPHIC DESIGN
- **SOFT SKILLS**

- TIME MANAGEMENT TWO JOBS WHILE IN SCHOOL FAST LEARNER
- TRAINER AT PAST TWO COMPANIES COMMUNICATION
- SELECTED AS TROUBLESHOOTER
- · LEADERSHIP

RANKED IN TOP 20 EDUCATORS

- FIGMA
- ILLUSTRATOR
- PHOTOSHOP
- JAVASCRIPT

WORK EXPERIENCE

CAREER COACH

Equus, Terre Haute, IN

2024 - current

- · Counseled individuals on the value of continuing education while advancing their careers.
- · Developed and implemented career coaching programs for clients based on
- individual needs, interests, and goals.
 Identified areas of improvement needed for successful job placement by analyzing
- gaps between current qualifications and desired positions.

 Provided guidance on job searching techniques such a resume writing, networking, interviewing and salary negotiation.

Member Service Representative

Sam's Club, Terre Haute, IN

— 2019 - 2023

- Provided exceptional customer service for 4 years in a fast-paced environment ensuring customers' needs were met and issues were promptly resolved.
- · Sold a minimum of 10 memberships a day and led the company in Scan and Go member downloads and uses for 2 years.
- Exhibited leadership by mentoring new hires and less experienced associates on providing knowledgeable, friendly service.
 Provided service to 100+ members a day to solve problems, handle complaints,
- sell memberships and accept returns.
- · Coached over 50 new customer service associates on store policies, POS systems, and customer service best practices, ensuring smooth onboarding and
- Commended by management for ability to de-escalate difficult situations and resolve customer conflicts.

Teacher

Vigo County Schools, Terre Haute, IN

— 2017 - 2023

- · Managed and maintained coursework for 350+ students.
- Enhanced instruction using ongoing assessment to track educational gaps. Developed school social media sites.
- Enhanced school website
- Selected to maintain all computers and technology.
- Trained over 50 staff members on all new technology and learning managements systems

PROJECTS

Coursework

Picshare

Picshare is a native app for both iOS and Android. It is designed for users create circles of trusted members to share photos and memories with. Picshare creates a safe space to share photos avoiding the risk of social media. . The app was created using FIGMA and Adobe Photoshop.

Stashfast

Stashfast is a responsive app designed to assist users in budgeting and to save money for large purchases. It allow users to track spending, create goals for savings money, and earn badges for meeting goals. It is a fun way to handle finances. The app was created using FIGMA, Adobe Photoshop and Canva

Macromakers

Macromakers is a responsive app for users that are on a health journey that want to want to curate meal plans to prep meals for the week using their chosen nutritional values. Users are able to utilize the app's capability to calculate values for them or input on their own. . The app was created using FIGMA